engineering.com 2019-07-17

# ENGINEERING.com | Privacy Policy

## Introduction

We at Engineering.com, Inc. ("engineering.com") are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need to protect any personal identification information ("Personal Information") you share with us. Accordingly, engineering.com has established this Online Privacy Policy.

This privacy policy applies to all sites owned and operated by Engineering.com, Inc. including www.engineering.com, www.eng-tips.com, www.tek-tips.com, projectboard.engineering.com, www.tenlinks.com, www.engineersrule.com and www.caddigest.com.  

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify you, including, but not limited to, your first and last name, your home or work address and an email address or other contact information. We have designed engineering.com's web pages in such a way that you can visit most public areas without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself.

Engineering.com strives to comply with relevant privacy legislation around the world. Our goal is to provide protection for your Personal Information regardless of where that Personal Information is collected or stored.

## Tracking your site visits

Some of our Web pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used to collect information about Web site activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personal Information previously indicated by a Web user. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve certain ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

We also may use tracking technology to capture your Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types. We use this and related information to improve our Web site our service to all visitors.

## Tracking your subscriber information

We collect Personal Information supplied by our users who register or who choose to provide their profile data to access certain areas or information on engineering.com. This profile data allows us to better match our content to the needs of our audience. For example, if your engineering specialty is “mechanical” you will be more likely to be presented with content that is specifically aimed at mechanical engineers. Engineering.com is a free service that is supported by advertising, so we also use this data to better match advertisements and promotions to our audience.

## Choice

You may choose whether or not to provide Personal Information to engineering.com. If you choose not to provide the Personal Information we request, you can still visit most of engineering.com's Web pages, but you may be unable to access certain pages and the services that they contain. 

## Security

Wherever your Personal Information may be held within engineering.com or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the Personal Information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.

## Access/Accuracy

To the extent that you do provide us with Personal Information, engineering.com wishes to maintain accurate Personal Information. Where we collect Personal Information from you on the Web, our goal is to provide a means of contacting engineering.com should you need to update or correct that Information.

## Sharing of Data with Third Parties

Third parties provide certain services, such as email list maintenance, available on engineering.com or on our behalf. Engineering.com may provide information, including Personal Information, that engineering.com collects to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information, and services. Engineering.com will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect Personal Information on engineering.com's behalf.

If you choose to provide us with your Personal Information, we may transfer that Information within engineering.com, to engineering.com's third-party service providers as required, and to advertisers whose information you have viewed or downloaded. Transferring this information may mean that your data travels across borders. By registering to access content from one of our advertisers the advertiser may contact you by telephone, email, direct email or other common forms of communication using the information you provided.

Other than as stated herein, engineering.com does not intend to transfer Personal Information without your consent to third parties who are not bound to act on engineering.com's behalf unless such transfer is legally required.

While we cannot guarantee absolute privacy, we will address any issue to the best of our abilities as soon as possible. Feel free to contact us to raise any privacy issues that concern you at [**info@engineering.com**](mailto:info@engineering.com).

## Your Consent

By using this Web site, you consent to the terms of our Online Privacy Policy and to engineering.com's processing of Personal Information for the purposes given above as well as those explained where engineering.com collects Personal Information on the Web. Should the Online Privacy Policy change, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that these changes are posted prominently on our web site for a reasonable period of time.

If you wish to make changes to the newsletters you receive, or to revoke your consent to share your Personal Information under the terms provided here, you can update your preferences by logging into engineering.com, selecting your profile icon, and choosing “manage preferences”. 

## Specific Policies for Jurisdictions outside of the U.S.A.

If you are a resident of Canada or Europe, you will see additional language upon registration that explains exactly what engineering will do with your personal data, including the circumstances under which it may be shared with our advertising partners so that they may in turn contact you. The language reads as follows: 

By subscribing to a topic area, you expressly consent to receive news and information that Engineering.com's editors select to match your interests. You also agree to receive invitations to view educational resources such as white papers, webinars and offers from our sponsors. If you explicitly request to download or view a resource that is marked as sponsored you agree that engineering.com may share your registration data with the sponsors identified on the request page and that any such sponsor may contact you electronically.

You will have to proactively select that you agree with this policy in order to receive newsletters, and you will be asked to agree again with this policy each time you request access to a piece of gated content.
